[Fate Chooses You]
[Episode 29]
[Tomb of My Mentor, Duan Xianyin]
What's going on?
It's Fan.
[Liubo Temple]
-Master!
What is this?
Xin Mei.
Senior.
Senior!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Your immortal perception is still here.
They didn't extract
your immortal perception.
There's a note for you.
[Come to the pear tree
in Tongyu Alley quickly]
Who sent it?
I don't know.
While I was out shopping,
someone slipped it into my pouch.
You didn't notice who it was?
Eighty-year-old Suquan wine.
You can't bear to spare me a cup?
Everyone is looking for you,
while you're here, all relaxed.
I would have come even if
they weren't looking for me.
Why do something unnecessary?
What a boast.
You sent me a message.
Weren't you afraid I'd bring people along?
You wouldn't.
I have investigated you.
You are Fu Tian's direct disciple.
In the 10 years since you joined
the Qinghong Sect,
you have become
one of the Eight Vajras.
Previously, at the Yunhan Inn,
you and I joined forces
to kill Dharma King Wenyin.
Back then, I thought you were
just fighting among yourselves.
But later at the paper mill,
you gave me hints in secret.
I really want to know
why you betrayed Fu Tian
to help me.
Why did I help you?
Don't you know?
Because I like you.
You are good-looking,
smart, handsome,
and very prudish.
I...
like men like you.
Why don't you
stop looking for that stubborn girl
from Xin Xie Manor
and be a couple with me
instead?
I'm smart, beautiful,
and younger than her.
Moreover,
I am sensible and interesting.
Unlike her, she's so reckless
and causes a lot of trouble.
You like me?
It's love at first sight.
No wonder you wrote to Chu Ying,
notifying him to come and save me.
You must really love me
and have never set me up before.
You really came prepared.
That's right.
I did it.
Since you investigated me,
did you discover
Qinghong Sect's big secret?
Secret?
Man lives but one life,
like a plant lives through one autumn.
Time flies and is ruthless.
Who in this world
doesn't want to be extraordinary
and transcend the cycle of life and death?
But without immortal perception,
you cannot enter the door of cultivation.
Even if you are an emperor or general
holding absolute power,
or a wealthy merchant
owning vast riches,
as long as you have
no immortal perception,
you are destined to be
a mortal in this life.
Do you want to know how Fu Tian
took less than a century
to make Qinghong Sect
the number one sect in North Xiang?
Because he has a way
to let ordinary people without
immortal perception
cross the vast chasm,
enter the immortal sect,
and become cultivators.
Master.
Regardless of your gender
or your aptitude,
as long as he is willing,
he can make you break through
your limits overnight,
refine your form, and grant you rebirth.
Mortals can become cultivators,
and cultivators
can also nourish themselves
to elevate their realms.
Thank you, Master.
Aren't you curious
about how he did it?
That's such an important secret.
If I ask you,
will you tell me?
There's nothing that can't be said.
I just want you to see it for yourself.
It's a grand matter.
It'd be a pity if you don't
witness it firsthand.
You don't have immortal perception either?
All members of the Qinghong Sect
were transformed from ordinary people.
Cultivators are not trusted.
Why?
Because Fu Tian believes that
only those who have truly been mortals
can genuinely hate the immortal sect.
Only when a moral body
crosses the boundary
between immortals and mortals
can one be firmly controlled by him.
But you still betrayed him.
Betray him?
That sounds too harsh.
It seems
you still don't understand Qinghong Sect.
Take me, for example.
I grew up in Qinghong Sect
since I was a child.
From the first day Fu Tian brought me back
to Qinghong Sect,
he told me
that my parents and clansmen
were all killed by the immortal sect.
I am an orphan
bearing a blood feud.
Haven't you ever doubted
whether what Fu Tian said
was right or wrong?
That's why I said you don't understand.
In Qinghong Sect,
there are many children
just like me.
Everyone is deeply immersed
in the same hatred.
Under such conditions,
discipline is most easily implemented.
Everyone is working hard
towards the same goal,
foolishly
yet firmly.
They work their fingers to the bone
every day.
Everyone calls me a demonic enchantress.
I also like this title myself.
I even mocked them
for being short-sighted,
unable to discern
good from evil in this world,
or notice the hypocrisy
of the immortal sect.
Until one day,
I found out that
Qinghong Sect was sending medicine
to the immortal sect.
What medicine?
You must have seen this too.
The Yangyuan Pill
commonly eaten by the immortal sect?
That's right.
They often use this medicine
to increase their skills,
repair their Qihai,
and nourish their bodies.
Why do you have this?
I got this
from the Bishui Branch.
At that time, the Branch Master
drank this golden liquid
and improved his skills greatly.
He even advanced on the spot.
I once asked Su Taiyi
about the origin of this golden liquid.
He said it had similar ingredients
to the Yangyuan Pill.
Not similar.
They are exactly the same thing.
This golden liquid
is extracted from the immortal perception
of cultivators.
The higher the cultivator's realm,
the purer the extracted golden liquid,
and the greater
the energy it provides.
The Yangyuan Pills
are simply pills made from very diluted
golden liquid.
So,
Qinghong Sect
is extracting golden liquid
from the immortal perception
of cultivators.
A portion of it
is used to transform
mortals into cultivators,
while the other portion
is made into Yangyuan Pills
and resold to the immortal sect.
Sounds ridiculous, right?
Claiming to hate the immortal sect,
but wanting to become the immortal sect
and rely on it.
Many of my friends
died while fighting
against the immortal sect.
If Qinghong Sect
is a vassal of the immortal sect...
If everything is fake,
then what about the people who died?
Lord Baori of our sect
is someone sent by
the immortal sect of Central Plains.
Lu Qianqiao.
I know you are a War Demon.
After the Battle of Pinghu,
the War Demons disappeared.
You are a loner now.
You don't belong to the War Demons,
the Human Race,
and certainly not the immortal sect.
These years,
I suppose your life
hasn't been easy either.
You should understand the feeling
of working hard for a goal
since childhood,
only to find out
in the end that
everything is a scam.
I, Zuo Yingying, considered myself smart,
but I was deceived,
lied to,
and played for a fool by them.
Why?
What do you want to do?
I want to try.
Try what?
I want to try
to kill Fu Tian,
destroy the Qinghong Sect,
and break this cage that imprisons me.
How about it?
Shall we cooperate?
It won't be the first time, anyway.
[Phoenix City]
Phoenix City is 1 of the 3 towns
in the Western Regions.
It connects Mohe to the east,
Banchi to the west,
and Xiongshan to the south.
Since ancient times,
it has been a prosperous place for trade.
After the Battle of Pinghu,
the Emperor of the Human Race
took the opportunity
to recover Phoenix City
and sent soldiers to garrison here.
Nominally, Phoenix City
is under the jurisdiction
of the Central Plains.
But in fact,
the Qinghong Sect has infiltrated
every corner.
Once the people of the Wushuang Society
and the immortal sect
step into this place,
they will be within
our line of sight.
Then why did you let them
burn down the Sihe Library?
Because it's not important.
The people of the Wushuang Society
care about the Unparalleled Secret Magic.
But the Qinghong Sect is different.
Although we have no immortal perception,
we also practice the art of cultivation.
The Qinghong Sect members
practice with secret methods,
vainly attempting to use mortal bodies
to become immortals and saints.
From this perspective,
the Wushuang Society is also our enemy.
Then why did you collect ancient books
and build the Sihe Library?
Because that's a trap.
As long as the Sihe Library is there,
groups of people from the Wushuang Society
will come here.
As long as they come,
the immortal sect members will come after.
There is a saying in the Central Plains:
the mantis stalks the cicada,
unaware of the oriole behind.
That's exactly it.
After the immortal sect members
and your group
wounded each other in battle,
our people took the opportunity to act.
Now, most of them
are locked in the dungeon of our sect,
including Xin Mei,
her junior,
and your swordsman friend.
Lord of Rust-Sword isn't dead?
Not at all.
He's very lucky.
Can you help me
save them?
Master is certain
you'd go back to save them,
and has set up an inescapable trap
for you.
He also sent his Right Protector,
Lord Tiling, to guard the dungeon.
He's a cultivator in the Void Stage.
With such a huge risk,
why should I help you?
I will help you kill Fu Tian,
destroy the Qinghong Sect,
and break the cage imprisoning you.
By yourself?
What do you mean?
Am I not also here?
What's your plan?
Three days later,
Qinghong Sect will be holding
the ritual assembly.
I heard Fu Tian will recruit disciples
into the sect at the assembly.
According to you,
he'll use his secret arts
to help ordinary mortals
cross the boundary
between mortals and immortals
and step into
the Cultivation Realm, right?
I will kill him in public that day.
Come in.
How is it?
What about you, Senior?
They used the Nine Breaths Technique
to seal off our acupoints
and nine apertures.
They severed our connection
to the spiritual energy
of heaven and earth.
Even if I forcefully activate
the spiritual energy in my body,
it will soon be suppressed and sealed.
I can't break through it at all.
Break!
Even if you trigger
all the power in the formation,
you still can't break the seal.
And it might cause
the two forces to clash,
making it backfire on you
and cost you your life.
Then what do we do now?
Just wait for death?
Watch your tone.
If I had known,
I would have learned more from my father
about the formation to break seals.
Then we wouldn't be
sitting ducks like this today.
How are you?
If my Divine Sword were here,
I'd have been able to
gather qi with my sword will
and break this damn seal.
If my father were here,
the people outside would be dead by now.
How pointless.
Slower. I told you to be slower.
You're still too fast.
You need to be slower.
Even slower?
Can such a weak move
even hit anyone?
The path of cultivation
is about understanding the Dao
and practicing methods,
gathering qi and condensing power
to defeat the enemy.
The key is that you must understand
what Dao you cultivate,
what method you practice,
what qi you gather,
and what power you utilize.
Master, you once said that
we righteous cultivators
cultivate the Dao of Heaven,
gather the qi of the five elements,
and utilize pure spiritual power.
The path of cultivation
is a path of defying heaven
to fight for life.
Remember not to just memorize by rote.
Please enlighten me, Master.
As for the Dao of Heaven,
I will properly explain them to you
another day.
Today, I'll first tell you about
the qi of the five elements.
The qi of the five elements
is divided into clear and turbid.
Clear qi is pure and immaculate.
The more you absorb,
the stronger the spiritual power
you condense.
And the turbid qi?
Turbid qi is chaotic and uncontrollable.
If you accidentally
inhale the slightest bit,
it will corrode your immortal perception,
making it impossible for your cultivation
to improve any further.
Is there no one in this world
who mainly cultivates turbid qi?
There are.
Heretical cultivator, for example.
Of course, they have almost been wiped out
by me.
But I don't understand.
Both types belong
to the qi of the five elements.
Why are those
who mainly cultivate turbid qi
called heretical cultivators?
That's because
they are eager for quick success
and have improper intentions.
It has nothing to do with turbid qi.
So does that mean
turbid qi can also
condense into powerful spiritual energy?
Yin alone cannot exist;
Yang alone cannot grow.
In theory, this is true.
But no one in this world
can successfully cultivate turbid qi,
nor can anyone use it to prove their Dao.
My disciple,
remember this.
All things share the same source.
Heaven and earth are originally connected.
Absorbing clear qi is the foundation.
The state of mind has no beginning or end.
Clouds roll and unroll.
Wind comes and goes in emptiness.
Firmly guard the true original intent.
Do not let the turbid become a flood.
Senior, did you think of something?
The Nine Breaths Technique
has used the Five Elements
to sever our connection
with heaven and earth's spiritual power.
But,
it has only sealed
our spiritual energy from clear qi.
Isn't that enough?
Under the vast Dao of Heaven,
it's not like we can only gather
clear qi into energy.
What if I do the opposite?
You mean,
we can turn turbid qi
into energy instead?
Exactly.
No.
Do you have a better idea, Sheng?
Then let me take the risk.
Among us,
I’m the only one
at the Nascent Soul Stage.
So,
if we want to expel the clear
and gather the turbid,
I have the highest chance
of breaking the seal.
What are you arguing about?
When heaven and earth were created,
mountains stood, and rivers flowed.
The two qis operated wonderfully within,
parallel without conflict.
The light and clear yang qi
rose to become heaven,
while the heavy and turbid yin qi
sank to become earth.
Where qi gathers in abundance,
conception occurs.
Where qi comes alive and stirs,
nurturing begins.
Where qi fuses and binds,
the fetus takes form.
Where qi briefly comes to rest,
breath is drawn.
Yin and yang
represent death and life,
clear and turbid.
They complement each other
and are born together.
But during cultivation,
one must reject the turbid
and accept the clear
to enrich their origin,
fuel the cycle,
and generate endless energy.
So,
in simple terms,
what does that mean?
Ignorant.
Xin Mei is planning
to do the opposite.
She plans to absorb the turbid qi here,
turn it into power,
break the seal from the outside,
and lift the Nine Breaths Technique
that is trapping us here.
Isn't that a good thing?
But turbid qi is chaotic
and uncontrollable.
One mistake, and it will
corrode her immortal perception,
making it impossible for her
to improve her cultivation.
Senior.
Let me try.
Sheng.
I am already
a Nascent Soul cultivator.
So many people can never reach
the Nascent Soul stage in their lifetime.
I am already very content.
The Qinghong Sect
has malicious intentions.
Not only did they imprison us,
but they also had ulterior
motives for Lu Qianqiao.
Our lives may be in danger
at any moment.
We must escape from here quickly.
That person seems to be
from the Wang family of Jinqiu.
Why is he here?
You are good at formations.
Can you set one up to help me?
No.
This method is too harmful.
I can't set you up for failure.
Tell me.
The conditions to activate this formation
are extremely strict.
I have never tried it.
I don't even know
if I can succeed.
First,
we need to gather the impure variations
of the five elements
and turbid qi itself.
Foul stagnant water can be impure water.
Filthy soil from a prison
can be impure earth.
Then we still need impure metal,
impure wood,
and impure fire.
Does qi count?
Yes.
Will sword qi work?
Sword qi is indeed metal,
but it must be impure metal.
What is impure metal?
Generally speaking,
anything tainted with resentment,
anger,
decay,
sorrow, disaster,
obscenity, cruelty, pain, disease,
murderous intent, and the like
can be called impure metal.
Are impure wood and impure fire
the same?
Yes.
I can summon the Divine Sword
to arouse
the murderous intent in my heart.
A murderous blade would be impure.
I will handle the fire.
A resentful fire is considered impure.
Then I will handle the wood.
A decaying dead wood is considered impure.
Okay.
Then we have them all.
Master has arrived!
Welcome, Master.
♪ Pointing to the sky,
questioning the moon ♪
♪ I'd rather be a wandering immortal
in the mortal world ♪
♪ And experience it all for myself ♪
♪ Right and wrong, justice and evil ♪
♪ In all the world,
I choose first the people ♪
The murderous blade you gathered
is too weak.
I can't form the formation this way.
♪ How could the powerful lie drunk
in golden halls ♪
♪ Illusions of heaven
and memory entwined ♪
♪ I will still break
into this mortal realm ♪
♪ To demand a rightful ending ♪
Greetings, Master.
May the Sect Leader
shine as eternal as the sun and moon.
share the glory of heaven and earth.
Today
is the birthday of the Phoenix God,
and also an auspicious day
when the Phoenix God descends to bless
all living beings.
The Phoenix God traverses heaven and earth
as the Lord of all gods.
We should follow the Phoenix God
to eradicate all evil in the world,
achieve unprecedented feats,
be granted righteous status,
and ascend to heaven
to live forever with the Dao.
Dao of Heaven, may we never age.
Live as long as the earth,
and ascend to heaven soon.
May my life be prolonged
to live forever with the Dao.
Greetings, Vajra.
Today, the sect is holding
a blessing ceremony.
To prevent scoundrels from
the immortal sect from causing trouble,
you must be on full alert.
Do not slack off.
Yes.
Are you ready?
I am going to start the formation.
Bring it on.
The Five Elements are born,
each with its own nature.
Their essences miraculously
combine and condense.
The interaction of two energies
creates everything.
All things multiply and change endlessly.
Activate!
Who is fortunate enough
to join the sect today?
Where is Wang Yanqing?
Devout follower Wang Yanqing is here.
Congratulations on the birthday
of the Phoenix God.
I congratulate
our God and the Sect Master.
May you be as enduring as the moon,
and as radiant as the sun.
Report to the Phoenix God,
and tell everyone present,
who you are.
I come from the Wang family of Jinqiu.
I'm the direct heir of the Wang family.
The Wang family of Jinqiu
has produced cultivators in the past,
so it can be considered
a family of cultivators.
As far as I know,
your family has always been
subordinate to the immortal sect,
serving them.
So why do you
want to join our Qinghong Holy Sect now?
You may not know this, Venerable.
Over the years,
our Wang family may seem
to be driven by the immortal sect,
but in reality,
we are forced to serve
by their despotic power.
They are cruel and ruthless,
and do not treat us as humans at all.
They take whatever
they want from my family,
and the slightest hesitation from us
would bring fatal disaster.
Who in your family
has been harmed by the immortal sect?
My father
and elder brother
were both killed by the immortal sect.
Our Wang family has been driven
to a dead end by the immortal sect.
The reason I could
find my way here today
is that
I felt the calling of the Phoenix God.
I am willing to offer
all my family's wealth.
Have mercy on me, Sect Master.
Please allow me into the sect.
Give me guidance and enlighten me.
One day,
the people of the immortal sect
will pay in blood.
Blood for blood!
Wang Yanqing,
were the words you just said
truly from your heart?
I swear to the Phoenix God,
everything I, Wang Yanqing, said is true.
If there is even half a lie,
may I incur the wrath of gods and men,
be pierced by a sword,
and die without a whole corpse.
Please pass your judgment, Master.
Since that is the case,
I will represent you today
to pray to the Phoenix God.
May the Phoenix God grant us guidance.
Thank you, Phoenix God.
Thank you for your grace, Phoenix God.
Thank you for your mercy, Master.
Rise.
The Phoenix God
has felt your devotion.
From now on,
we are close siblings
of the same family.
The Phoenix God will bless you
and guide you when you are lost.
All believers of the Qinghong Sect
are united with you as one,
sharing life and death.
Thank you, Master.
You said you have a deep hatred
for the immortal sect.
Today,
I will use the blood of the immortal sect
to baptize
and bless you.
I will follow your arrangements, Master.
Should I seize power,
I will fight the immortal sect to the end.
Pick a prisoner from the immortal sect
and bring them here.
Yes.
Senior.
How are you?
I'm fine.
It's done.
I will quickly
undo the Nine Breaths Technique for you.
Adjust your breath
and steady yourself first.
What happened to you?
I had to damage my own vitality
to gather the turbid qi of dead wood.
Someone is coming.
Look at your short-lived face.
You'll do.
Don't be impulsive.
It's okay.
I'll go.
If I am lucky enough to survive,
I will kill all of you.
If I die,
remember to avenge me.
Don't rush.
It'll be your turn next.
Let's go.
Who is it?
The Blessing Ceremony is held today.
What are you doing here
instead of tending to sect matters?
Then what are you doing here?
Waiting for you.
Then you are really lucky.
You waited and met me.
Stop!
Master was right.
You really are a traitor.
Bring him up.
Move.
I can walk myself.
Kneel.
Behave yourself.
Look at where you are.
Where I am?
What a big cesspit.
Are all of you
lining up to use the toilet?
Slap him.